Ushioh?
潮？
Again? Quit looking like you saw a ghost.
又來了，真是的，一副看到鬼的表情
You're only supposed to appear on the 24th!
你不是應該在24日才會出現的嗎？
What? Why do you know that?
甚麼…你是怎麼知道的？
What?
甚麼？
Listen, Shinpei. You might not believe this,
聽著，慎平，你或許無法相信
but something terrible happens on the 24th.
但24日那天會發生可怕的事
Everyone gets swallowed up by some black shadow monster and disappears.
那個像黑色影子的東西會把大家吞噬 所有人都會消失
Wait… You…
等一下，你…
Did you come from that festival too?
你難道也是 從那個夏日慶典上來的嗎？
What? Did you too?
甚麼？難道慎平也是嗎？
I washed my eyes so I feel a bit better now.
洗完臉感覺好多了
Wh-What?
怎麼了？
That smell! Are you making curry?
這香味莫非是咖喱？
Y-Yes.
答對了
Ah, I should've thought of that.
天啊，竟然還有這一招
Shinpei! Your stomach growled so loud! Just like Sis.
小慎肚子叫得好大聲，像姐姐一樣
Thank goodness. That means you're feeling better.
太好了，肚子會餓說明你恢復精神了
I guess so…
算是吧
Calm down, and focus on making the curry.
冷靜，俯瞰做咖喱的步驟，冷靜下來
This situation is not good.
這情況很不妙啊
Ms. Nagumo… this isn't just a small difference.
南雲老師，這根本就不只是 「不一樣的事」這麼簡單
Ah, sorry Shinpei, it took so long for me to come back.
抱歉啊，慎平，我回來得太晚了
That Mr. Karikiri sure can talk.
雁切先生太多話了
Welcome back. It's almost done.
歡迎回來，亞倫，很快就能吃了
-Mio. -Yes?
澪
Why aren't you helping?
你怎麼沒幫忙？
My job is eating!
我只負責吃
Smells great. Ushio used to love that.
好香的味道
In five minutes, Alain goes to the washroom, Mio goes to the bathroom.
五分鐘左右後亞倫會去洗手間 澪會去廁所
Go to my room. Don't be seen.
你趁機去我房間，別被發現了
-Got it! -Does she even understand this situation?
好
FAKE CALL TO TOTSUMURA TELL SOU I'LL CALL HIM TOMORROW
（給凸村打報假警的電話 告訴窗明天再聯繫他）
All done!
好了，完成
Hey, where are you going?
奇怪，你要去哪裡？
Well… I'm going to eat in my room.
我…我回自己房間吃
Two plates?
吃兩碟？
W-Well, I'm super hungry.
不…我…真的很餓
Curry!
咖喱
-This is… the curry chant! -Curry, hm-hm-hm!
-咖喱 -這是咖喱節奏
-Shinpei's curry! -Damn it. Why is this happening?
-慎平的咖喱… -可惡，怎麼會這樣？
Don't let the words and the appearance of shadows affect you.
別被影子的外表和語言所動搖
Wow!
天啊
Can I eat?
我可以吃嗎？
Sure.
嗯
Yay! Thank you for this meal!
太好了，我不客氣了
Somehow, this shadow Ushio looped back with me.
影子潮，不知道為甚麼 這傢伙和我一起輪迴了
-Yum! -That has to be it.
-好好吃 -這麼想就解釋得通了
How did you get here?
你是怎麼來到這裡的？從哪裡來的？
What? I walked.
甚麼？當然是走過來了
I woke up on Omotohama Beach. Don't worry. No one saw me.
我一醒來就在萬年青沙灘了 不過放心吧，沒人看到我
It's a monster!
她是怪物
I'm like a monster.
我就像怪物一樣
I'll make sure no one sees me again.
我不會再讓別人發現我了
Monster? No…
怪物…沒那…
That's not true.
沒那回事
Ah… no. Sorry.
沒甚麼，抱歉
Ugh, I got goosebumps.
真是的，我都起雞皮疙瘩了
I can kill it. Just stab its shadow.
我能殺了她，只要用刀刺中她的影子
Look, it's not even a bit on guard.
看，這傢伙渾身都是破綻
But it did save me that time.
但她那個時候救了我…是吧？
It…
-她… -好好吃
Tokyo?
東京？
Alain's friend is in Tokyo.
亞倫有個朋友在東京
I'm going to stay there and go to culinary school.
我打算寄宿在那裡，上廚師學校
I won't go to a high school in Wakayama.
不考和歌山的高中了
What?
甚麼？
I made up my mind.
我已經決定了
You never told me.
我怎麼沒聽你說過？
It's not like I need to tell you.
我沒必要告訴你吧
How can you make such an important decision by yourself?
為甚麼？這麼重要的事 怎麼就擅自決定了？
Why can't I decide for myself?
為甚麼我不能自己做決定？
I'm not a Kofune.
我不能繼續當小舟家的孩子了
I need to start earning my own living.
我要早點靠自己賺錢
I hate constantly being a burden on you and Alain!
不能一直給亞倫和你們添麻煩
A burden?
麻煩？
Do you hate it here?
慎平不喜歡這裡嗎？
What? Why are you asking that?
甚麼？你怎麼會這麼理解？
No, Ushio.
不是的，潮
-Enough! I didn't even need to tell you! -I…
-算了，我不想跟你說了 -因為我…
-I'm the one who's had enough! -love you.
-我才不想跟你說話 -喜歡你
I don't want us to become family like this.
我不希望以這種形式和你做家人
Hey, Shinpei. Today's your last day.
慎平，今天是最後一天了
I want your curry for dinner.
晚飯我想吃你做的咖喱
What? I need to pack.
（窗口信封）
I'll make it for you next time.
下次吧
You dummy.
慎平是笨蛋
There was no next time. At one point, that's what I thought.
我還以為根本沒有下一次了
You finally made it for me. I'm glad.
你終於做給我吃了，太好了
I got to eat your curry again.
又能吃到慎平做的咖喱
I'm glad I'm alive.
活著真是太好了
Is it good?
好吃嗎？
I want seconds!
我要再來一碗
It's not as good when Dad makes it.
爸爸也做過這個咖喱 但感覺味道就是不太一樣
I really like yours the best.
果然還是慎平做的最好吃
This is Ushio. She's Ushio.
她是潮，是潮啊
I see. I'm glad.
是嗎？那就好
Hey, Shinpei. Will the same thing happen on the 24th?
慎平，這樣下去到了24日 還會發生同樣的事情嗎？
Yes. I'm trying to stop that.
嗯，我會想辦法阻止的
I'll help too.
我也來幫忙
I can't stand that monster ruining Hitogashima Island's summer festival.
我不希望日都島的夏日慶典 被那種怪物毀掉
And I definitely can't let Mio and the others disappear!
我更不希望看到澪和大家消失
Right. Me too. Let's stop it, together!
是啊，我也是，我們一起阻止吧
Okay!
嗯
Can you copy humans?
你可以複製人類嗎？
I guess not.
看來是不行啊
It is currently 8:45 p.m. Shadow Mio should appear in 10 minutes.
現在是晚上8點45分，再過十分鐘 影子澪應該就會出現了
How does your location look, Nezu?
你那邊情況怎麼樣？根津先生
No issues. Just a little breeze.
沒有異常，就是有點起風了
There's enough light in town. Any contact from Shinpei?
街燈的光很亮，慎平那邊有消息嗎？
None.
沒有
Don't rely on his foresight too much, Ryunosuke.
龍之介，別太過於依賴那小子的預知
Prey never moves the way we expect it to.
獵物可不會按照我們的想法去行動
Hunters always need to adapt.
狩獵要時常記得隨機應變，知道嗎
Roger that.
明白
ANY ISSUES?
是南雲老師傳來的，影子潮的存在 我該告訴她嗎？還是該說謊呢？
But…
（有異常嗎？）
-Shinpei? -Oh, yeah.
慎平？
Why are you still dressed like that?
說起來，你怎麼還穿著這件衣服？ 在家裡穿泳衣很奇怪吧
Huh? Oh yeah. Why…
還真的是這樣，為甚麼我會…
Why didn't it bother me until now?
之前我都沒覺得奇怪…
Hey!
喂，你…
What did you do?
你做了甚麼？
It wasn't me!
不是我做的
My swimsuit disappeared! Why?
泳衣消失了，為甚麼？
Is it because you copied the swimsuit?
因為是複製的泳衣吧？
Whatever! Just give me something to wear!
甚麼衣服都行，快借衣服給我穿
What? Mio's shadow is coming? Did you lock up?
甚麼？澪的影子會來嗎？ 關好門窗了嗎？
We're fine.
都關了，沒問題
Although, locking up probably won't help much.
但我覺得關上門窗也沒多大意義
It only takes a tiny gap for a shadow to slip through.
那些傢伙可以潛入影子裡 稍微有點縫隙都能鑽進來
Really? Let me try!
甚麼？我也來試試
Don't worry. It hasn't come in here.
也不用擔心 那傢伙從來沒進入家裡過
Not once.
迄今為止一次都沒有
Shinpei?
小慎？
It's Mio! Hide!
是澪，快躲起來
Are you finished eating?
你吃完了嗎？
I wanna wash the dishes.
我想把碟子拿去洗了
Ah, the dishes. Sure.
對了，碟子
You all done? What? You used two spoons?
嗯，吃完了嗎？奇怪 你用了兩隻湯匙嗎？
Two glasses too.
還用了兩個杯子
Is that so strange? Nope, not at all!
這有甚麼奇怪的嗎？不奇怪吧 一點都不奇怪吧
Why sound formal all of a sudden? Sis isn't here, is she?
為甚麼突然說標準口音？ 難道姐姐在這裡嗎？
You made this bowl for her, didn't you?
畢竟小慎也做了姐姐的那份吧
I'm sure she's here.
姐姐一定在的
On Hitogashima Island, souls return home as guardian spirits.
日都島上死去的人的靈魂 會回到家裡來，成為家裡的守護神
Mr. Karikiri always said that.
雁切先生是這麼說的
Ah… You can leave the bowls. I'll wash them later.
是啊，碟子先放著吧，待會我來洗
Okay. Thanks for the meal, Shinpei.
嗯，謝謝你的咖喱，小慎
Yikes. That was a close one.
太可怕了，命也短了幾年
Mio does have good instincts.
澪有時候直覺很敏銳的
What is it? Forgot something?
怎麼了？還有甚麼事嗎？
What the…
咦？
It's not…
不對…
Ushioh!
潮
That hurt!
很痛啊
I can't beat it in a fight.
我打不贏她
But if I'm going to die anyway, I'll try everything I can do!
但是反正都要死，至少要做點甚麼 我現在唯一能做的事
Come on then, Mioh. I'll take you on!
來吧，澪，我來當你的對手
Sh-Shinpei.
慎平
Sis, why are you on his side?
姐姐，為甚麼要幫小慎？
He's with Nezu and Minakata, who kill shadows.
他可是殺了影子的根津和南方的同伴
So the fake doesn't have the same instincts.
甚麼啊？冒牌貨還真遲鈍
I love Shinpei. What's wrong with helping someone I love?
我喜歡慎平，幫助喜歡的人 有甚麼不對嗎？
But you died.
你明明已經死了
Sis died.
姐姐你都已經死了
You died!
你已經死了啊
Shin…
慎…
What did I tell you?
所以我都說了
It hurts…
好痛啊
Why? Shinpei…
為甚麼？小慎，我也…
Shinpei… I too…
我也對小慎…
Ushioh. Hey, stay with me, Ushioh!
潮，喂，堅持住啊，潮
Coming in.
打擾了
Ms. Nagumo…
南雲老師
Why get in my way?
為甚麼要妨礙我？
I am glad you are safe, Shinpei.
慎平先生平安無事，我很高興
But look at that. It's a shadow.
不過那是甚麼？是影子吧
I'm going to kill it. Get out of my way.
好了，讓開吧，我來殺掉她
I-I won't!
不，我不讓開
Did that shadow get into your head?
那影子向你灌輸了甚麼嗎？
I told you they can trick you if you keep talking to them.
我說過了吧 和影子談太久會被迷惑的
I know you begrudge shadows and want to kill them all.
我知道老師您痛恨影子 我也理解您要驅逐所有影子的目的
But this one protected me twice, sacrificing itself.
但是她救了我兩次 她拚上了性命去保護我
It doesn't think before it acts. It's Ushio!
她就是那個做事不考慮後果 就算考慮過也會先動手的笨蛋潮
So, please heal its injury…
所以拜託老師您幫她療傷
like you healed my arm!
就像您之前幫我治療手臂那樣 拜託您幫她處理傷口
Unbelievable.
你真是的…
Letting it go is one thing, but actually healing it?
懇求我放過她的話，我還能理解 竟然要我幫她處理傷口
If you side with shadows, I'll kill you too.
如果你站在影子那邊 我會把你也殺了
Fine.
沒關係
I'll just loop back and persuade you next time.
到時候我會再次輪迴 下一次我一定會說服老師的
Shinpei.
慎平
Where's Mio? Is the real Mio okay?
澪呢？真正的澪沒事吧
Oh… She's…
那個…我…
The real one is in the bath.
她本人在洗澡
I checked.
我剛才確認過了
Really?
真的嗎？
I see. Great.
是嗎？太好了
It's the same voice.
是同一個聲音
Nagu… Can… hear…
-南雲老師，聽到嗎？ -和拜託我來島上的聲音一樣
Adapt? Fine.
隨機應變啊，好吧
Show me your injury.
讓我看看你的傷口
Ushio Kofune sent me that message.
錄下那個訊息給我的人就是小舟潮
No way! Wait! My arm disappeared!
不是吧，等等，我的手臂消失了
U-Ushioh?
潮
Huh? It doesn't hurt.
奇怪，不痛了
That injury is a projection of the damage felt by the actual shadow.
那個傷是影子本身受到傷害的投影吧
A normal method won't heal it. So be careful of…
一般的處理方式是治不好的 所以今後千萬不能大意…
It's cool, if it doesn't hurt.
無所謂，反正只要不痛就行
You got over that too quick.
你也變得太快了吧
You are so big now.
不過你真的是長大了啊
I am Hizuru Minakata. You probably don't remember me.
我是南方日鶴，你應該不記得我了吧
I used to come to Bistro Kofune a lot.
以前我常去小舟西餐廳吃飯
Really? Sorry. I don't remember that.
真的嗎？抱歉，我不記得了
Listen to this.
你聽一下這個
Summer festival…
夏日慶典
…everybody was killed by shadows…
大家都會被影子所殺
Only Shinpei Ajiro… can stop…
能阻止這一切的只有網代慎平
Please help. Please.
需要老師的力量 拜託您了，請您一定要…
Do you recall this message?
你記得這個訊息嗎？
What is that? It's my voice.
這是甚麼？是我的聲音吧
This is the reason I came here. So you don't remember?
這就是我回到島上的理由 你沒印象，對吧？
No.
嗯
I see. Fine, forget it.
是嗎？那就算了，請你忘了吧
There's a bigger problem.
現在還有個更重要的問題
Why did the shadow Mio go inside the Kofune home?
為甚麼影子澪會闖進小舟家中？
The shadow Mio knew that Shiori was defeated.
影子澪知道了影子詩織被殺掉的事
Apparently, they are sharing information.
很明顯，那些傢伙之間有互通情報
Mioh was aware of us and decided to eliminate us.
看來影子澪知道是我們做的 所以前來消滅我們
It was after Nezu and me before…
到上一輪為止，她的目標是我和根津
but now it knew that Shinpei Ajiro was also with us.
這一輪她知道了 網代慎平也是我們的同伴
So Mioh entered your house to kill Shinpei Ajiro.
所以影子澪才會為了殺掉網代慎平 闖進家裡
Is it because I went with you to Koba Mart?
是因為我也一起去了小早超市嗎？ 可是到底是怎麼暴露的呢？
We destroyed all of the shadows that were there.
當時在場的影子應該都被殺掉了吧
In any case, I can't act with you anymore.
不管怎麼樣，接下來 我們都不能和你一起行動了
As long as you stay with Ushio's shadow.
如果你打算和影子潮一起行動的話
Ushioh may have saved you and doesn't seem a threat to us.
潮的確救了你 看樣子似乎也對我們沒有敵意
However, if Ushioh is broken, we don't know when she might get fixed.
但是就算潮真的出了故障
That is the most we can do.
這是我們所能做的最大讓步
Ms. Nagumo!
老師
At three o'clock tomorrow, Mio's shadow killed you in Shinju Forest.
老師在明天下午3點過後 會在鎮守森林被澪的影子殺害
We killed Mioh, but there may be others.
雖然影子澪被殺了 但可能會有其他的追捕者來
Please don't die!
請您絕對不要死
Destiny can be changed. This is a rare opportunity to prove that.
「命運是可以改變的」 這是個證明的絕佳機會
BISTRO KOFUNE LUNCH SPECIALS
（小舟西餐廳，特價午餐A，炸豬扒 B，炸白魚，C，拿坡里風意粉）
ALARM SNOOZE, STOP
（鬧鐘，延遲，關閉）
Shinpei.
慎平
Good morning.
早安
Oh… you were awake.
你醒了？
I'm hungry. And thirsty.
我肚子餓了，也口渴了
I'll bring you something.
我去樓下拿點東西給你吃
Thanks!
好
Oh, yeah.
對了
Yeah. Thanks, Tokiko. I feel better.
嗯，謝謝你，朱鷺子，我心情好點了
No, I'm sorry I kept you up. Bye.
沒有，抱歉一直拖著你聊到早上 嗯，先這樣了
Good morning, Shinpei.
早安，小慎
I'm up already, so you don't have to come wake me, okay?
我已經起來了，你不用到房間叫我了 就這樣
Uh… okay.
好的
She can't come wake me if I'm already up.
我都起床了 應該就不會再來叫我了吧
Wait, Shinpei!
等等，小慎
Mio gave you this?
澪給了你這個？
Yes. This is the original.
對，這個才是原版
Original.
原版
Does it make you remember anything? Like before you died?
看到這個有沒有想起來甚麼？ 比如死之前的事
Will you think about it?
你可以再想一會兒嗎？
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡？
We're opening the restaurant today.
今天店裡重新開始營業了
I see. That sounds like Dad.
是嗎？真像爸爸的作風
Yes, a restaurant is always there. It has to stay the same.
是的，餐廳要一如往常地開店 一如往常地在那裡
Alain always said that.
這是亞倫的口頭禪
I need to protect this simple everyday life.
一定要守護這理所當然的日常
Hi Shinpei. Sorry, was I too early?
嘿，慎平，抱歉，我是不是來早了？
Sorry for the wait.
久等了
-Hey. -Here.
-沒事 -這給你
An umbrella? It's super sunny today.
雨傘？今天可是大晴天啊
Just take it.
行了，你就帶著吧
What's with you? Such a weirdo.
甚麼啊？真是個奇怪的人
I'll get straight to the point.
我要說的事不是別的
I need to tell you something about Ushio's death.
關於潮的死因 有些情況我必須告訴你
Ligature marks, right? Someone may have killed me.
是吉川線的事吧，我有可能是被殺的
Right. Actually… Who are you?
是啊，其實…哇！你是誰？
Ushioh, you don't need the disguise anymore.
潮，不用變裝了
Ah… No… It can't be…
不是…甚麼…那…那個…
Ushio!
潮？
Yo.
嗨
He's frozen.
窗死機了
We told Sou everything.
我們把一切都告訴了窗
Sou quietly listened to everything we said.
這一次，窗也是沉默著聽到了最後
Sorry. If only I had done more to save her. If only…
對不起，那個時候如果我的急救 可以做得更好，當時如果我能更…
I know being sorry won't bring her back! But please…
我知道再怎麼道歉也挽回不了 所以至少…
Hit me! If not, I…
打我一頓吧，否則我會…
What a kick!
踢了
Stand up, Sou. Feel better?
站起來，窗，這樣你滿意了吧？
We are relying on you here. Quit whining!
我們還要指望你的，別再婆婆媽媽了
The private beach behind the elementary school.
小學後面的私人海灘
So I died here.
我就是死在這裡的啊
She really doesn't remember.
她真的完全不記得了
I want to see inside, but it's locked.
我想查一下裡面的東西，但手機鎖了
What? The password changed.
奇怪，密碼改了
By fingerprint.
我用了指紋解鎖
Open your email, memos, photos… Anything could help.
郵件、備忘錄，或者照片 甚麼都行，你快看看
There's a video file from the morning of the day before I died.
在我死的前一天早上有一條影片
That's it!
就是那個
Hold on. I'll play it.
等一下，我現在就播放